<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>alanza.xyz blog</title>
    <link>https://alanza.xyz/</link>
    <description>Robbie Lyman's personal blog</description>
    <generator>Robbie Lyman -- https://alanza.xyz</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 19:09:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
     <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
     <link>https://alanza.xyz/log/thoughts-on-learning/</link>
     <guid>https://alanza.xyz/log/thoughts-on-learning/</guid>
     <title>Thoughts on learning</title>
     <description>
       <span>&lt;div id=summary&gt;&lt;p&gt; I’ll go ahead and begin by claiming that generative AI has plateaued, if not already peaked. I might come back to justify that claim later on, but the purpose of this post is to share some musings on generative AI as a tool for accessing expertise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
       <a href="https://alanza.xyz/log/thoughts-on-learning/">Read More</a>
     </description>
    </item>
   
    <item>
     <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
     <link>https://alanza.xyz/log/return-statement/</link>
     <guid>https://alanza.xyz/log/return-statement/</guid>
     <title>return &quot;Robbie&quot;;</title>
     <description>
       <span>&lt;div id=summary&gt;&lt;p&gt; This summer I spent twelve weeks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://recurse.com&quot;&gt;The Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt;, a self-directed program that describes itself as “like a writer’s retreat, but for programmers”. Many participants write a “return statement” describing and reflecting on their time with the program. The name is a cute little pun: many functions in a computer program finish with a “return statement”, which allows the function to yield a bit of data as a result of the function’s execution. Anyway, this is mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
       <a href="https://alanza.xyz/log/return-statement/">Read More</a>
     </description>
    </item>
   
    <item>
     <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
     <link>https://alanza.xyz/log/for-completeness/</link>
     <guid>https://alanza.xyz/log/for-completeness/</guid>
     <title>For completeness: real numbers</title>
     <description>
       <span>&lt;div id=summary&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mathematics, if you squint, the word “real” has a kind of eldritch quality. Although calculus students work confidently with them, and they enable all kinds of nice behavior in topology, the definition of a /real number/ is, well, surreal. The title of this blog post is a pun. You might ask why we need the real numbers, and one answer is “for completeness”. For the same reason, I thought a blog post would be useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
       <a href="https://alanza.xyz/log/for-completeness/">Read More</a>
     </description>
    </item>
   
  </channel>
</rss>
